<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>com.dec05eba.gpu_screen_recorder</id>
    <name>GPU Screen Recorder</name>
    <summary>A shadowplay-like screen recorder for Linux. The fastest screen recorder for Linux</summary>
    <developer_name>dec05eba</developer_name>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
    <url type="homepage">https://git.dec05eba.com/gpu-screen-recorder/about/</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://git.dec05eba.com/?p=about</url>
    <url type="contribute">https://git.dec05eba.com/?p=about</url>
    <url type="donation">https://git.dec05eba.com/?p=about</url>

    <supports>
        <control>pointing</control>
        <control>keyboard</control>
    </supports>

    <description>
        <p>
            This is a screen recorder that has minimal impact on system performance by recording a monitor using the GPU only, similar to shadowplay on windows. This is the fastest screen recording tool for Linux. This screen recorder works with both X11 and Wayland.
        </p>
        <p>
            This screen recorder can be used for recording your desktop offline, for live streaming and for nvidia-like instant replay, where only the last few seconds are saved.
        </p>
        <p>
            There are some restrictions when recording on AMD/Intel or Wayland. Videos created on AMD/Intel/Wayland are in variable framerate format. Very out of date video players might have an issue playing such videos. I recommend using MPV or a browser to play such videos, otherwise you might experience stuttering in the video.
            Recording a monitor requires (restricted) root access which means that you have to install GPU Screen Recorder system-wide: flatpak install flathub --system com.dec05eba.gpu_screen_recorder
            and pkexec needs to be installed on the system and a polkit agent needs to be running.
            Some distros such as manjaro disable hardware accelerated H264/HEVC which means GPU Screen Recorder wont work on AMD/Intel and you have to either switch to another distro or install mesa from source (or install mesa-git for example).
        </p>
    </description>

    <launchable type="desktop-id">com.dec05eba.gpu_screen_recorder.desktop</launchable>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Simple view</caption>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dec05eba/com.dec05eba.gpu_screen_recorder/master/resources/screenshot1.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <caption>Advanced view</caption>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dec05eba/com.dec05eba.gpu_screen_recorder/master/resources/screenshot2.png</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>

    <releases>
        <release version="3.1.5" date="2023-07-25">
            <description>
                <p>AMD/Intel: Fix too dark video in the flatpak version.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.1.4" date="2023-07-23">
            <description>
                <p>AMD/Intel: Better color accuracy.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.1.3" date="2023-07-22">
            <description>
                <p>Fix capture on wlroots based wayland compositors. Fix cursor offset in amd/intel capture.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.1.2" date="2023-07-22">
            <description>
                <p>Support cursor capture on AMD/Intel on Wayland. Attempt to fix multi monitor offset capture in some cases.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.1.1" date="2023-07-21">
            <description>
                <p>Support cursor capture on AMD/Intel on Wayland.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.1.0" date="2023-07-21">
            <description>
            <ul>
                <li>Support wlroots capture when possible (no kms root access required)</li>
                <li>Make window capture a bit more robust</li>
                <li>Fix possible lag on recording start on AMD/Intel</li>
                <li>Make capture on AMD/Intel possible without Xwayland</li>
            </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.0.0" date="2023-07-18">
            <description>
                <p>Experimental wayland support on AMD/Intel/NVIDIA. Hotkeys not supported.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.2.0" date="2023-07-10">
            <description>
                <p>Attempt to fix screen recording when multiple graphics cards are connected</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.7" date="2023-07-07">
            <description>
                <p>Show proper error when running on wayland. Preparing for wayland support.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.6" date="2023-06-10">
            <description>
                <p>AMD/Intel: fix multi monitor capture coordinate being incorrect for some GPU driver versions.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.5" date="2023-05-22">
            <description>
                <p>Attempt to fix a recent nvidia (cuda) driver bug on RTX cards that causes a freeze when stopping recording.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.4" date="2023-05-17">
            <description>
                <p>Fix issue where the application freezes and keyboard freezes when selecting a new hotkey and another widget is clicked.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.3" date="2023-05-12">
            <description>
                <p>Attempt to fix possible issue on some systems with amd/intel where capture region is incorrect when multiple monitors are connected.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.2" date="2023-04-27">
            <description>
                <p>Attempt to fix possible audio/video sync on NVIDIA after recording for a long time. Temporary disable opus/flac because it breaks when recording multiple audio inputs.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.1" date="2023-04-22">
            <description>
                <p>AMD/Intel: Add support for capturing cursor when recording a monitor. Fix some cases of capture being glitched when using multiple monitors.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.0" date="2023-04-18">
            <description>
                <p>Enable AMD/Intel monitor capture. Requires the flatpak to be installed system-wide and it requires restricted root access. Record a single window if you dont like these restrictions. Videos created on AMD/Intel should be played with MPV otherwise it might have issues such as stuttering.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.0.0" date="2023-04-11">
            <description>
                <p>Add experimental support for AMD/Intel. Quality might not be well tuned yet and the video is in variable framerate mode, which might cause issues with some out of date video editing software or video players. Recording on AMD/intel is currently limited to a window (monitor capture is not possible yet).</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.3.5" date="2023-03-22">
            <description>
            <p>Show error when using wayland (because wayland is not supported)</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.3.4" date="2023-03-17">
            <description>
            <p>Add option to workaround a NVIDIA driver "bug" that causes framerate to drop a bit when recording (overclock memory transfer rate back to normal)</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.3.3" date="2023-03-11">
            <description>
            <p>Make it clear when graphics card is not supported</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.3.2" date="2023-03-04">
            <description>
            <ul>
                <li>Add VRR record option, only use with VRR as it might have driver issues!</li>
                <li>Add opus/flac audio options. opus/flac is only supported by .mp4/.mkv. Automatically changes audio codec if not supported by the container</li>
            </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.3.1" date="2023-02-22">
            <description>
            <p>Fix broken replay when recording with audio (possibly broken in normal recording as well)</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.3.0" date="2023-02-20">
            <description>
            <ul>
                <li>Switch to EGL (fixes possible window capture issues when using a compositor)</li>
                <li>Add option to change hotkeys</li>
                <li>Add option to merge audio tracks into one audio track</li>
                <li>Add option to follow the focused window</li>
                <li>Add option to force set h264/hevc (services such as discord can't play hevc videos directly in the application)</li>
                <li>Show proper error when NVIDIA GPU is not in use</li>
            </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.2.1" date="2022-11-24">
            <description>
            <p>Allow choosing between mp4, flv and mkv for record/replay. mkv survives system crashes</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.2.0" date="2022-10-27">
            <description>
            <p>Re-enable screen-direct, disable h264 forced fallback and use p6 again</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.8" date="2022-10-18">
            <description>
            <p>Attempt to fix stuttering in video that can happen sometimes (especially when vsync is enabled)</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.7" date="2022-10-16">
            <description>
            <p>Properly fallback to h264 if hevc is not supported by the gpu</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.6" date="2022-10-15">
            <description>
            <p>Fix livestreaming: flv does not properly fallback to h264</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.5" date="2022-10-11">
            <description>
            <p>Use lower preset on older gpus (kepler) and switch to h264 if h265 is not supported</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.4" date="2022-10-11">
            <description>
            <p>Tune options to try and reduce file size</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.3" date="2022-10-08">
            <description>
            <p>Better tune quality options for different resolutions</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.2" date="2022-10-07">
            <description>
            <p>Fix crash caused by invalid memory write when recording audio</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.1" date="2022-10-05">
            <description>
            <p>Fix possible pulseaudio crash</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.0" date="2022-10-05">
            <description>
            <p>Fixes some streaming issues (mostly metadata missing)</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0.0" date="2022-09-30"/>
    </releases>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
